Marvyn Zalewski

Security Architect

mszalewski@ownpixel.com / https://hexpy.fyi 22307 Hamburg

PROFILE

I am a Security Architect with over 2 years of experience assisting organizations and teams establishing and implementing security and privacy-by-design principles at all stages of product development. As a highly motivated and engaged Security Architect, I am driven by the mission to enable corporations to deliver secure products to their customers. In addition to my technical and organizational skills, I strive to build relationships based on trust and transparency with stakeholders and other teams. I understand the importance of clear communication and am able to bridge the gap between technical and non-technical stakeholders, ensuring that everyone is on the same page when it comes to security and privacy requirements.

EXPERIENCE

Security Architect - Jul 2022 - Present

AVIV Group / Hamburg

- Created meaningful KPIs to measure the teams effectiveness
- Planned, developed, and established a Security Architecture Culture program to promote security awareness and best practises across the organization
- Led the creation and implementation of the company's Secure Product Lifecycle program (SPLC) to ensure security is integrated throughout the whole product lifecycle
- Developed, and established critical security and architecture principles to ensure that they were in place prior to the implementation of the new joint AWS organization
- Developed the Security Architecture roadmap to align with business and department objectives

Security Officer Germany - Feb 2022 - Jan 2023

AVIV Group / Hamburg

- Conducted security assessments of the Immowelt IT landscape using the CIS (Center for Internet Security) framework to identify areas for improvement and missing security measurements
- Planned and partly implemented critical security and architecture principles to ensure that they were in place prior to the implementation of the new joint AWS organization
- Acted as the main contact for all german companies during the merger between all AVIV Group companies and collaborated with key stakeholders
- Supported the new central security capability to establish group wide measurements until all required positions were filled

Cyber Security Specialist - Okt 2021 - Jun 2022

immowelt Hamburg GmbH / Hamburg

- Developed and implemented a security maturity model to measure and effectively increase the security level of all engineering teams
- Acted as the main contact for all security related matters
- Established centralized security oriented processes like a Root Cause Analysis (RCA) process, an incident process, and guidelines covering how to handle certain security incidents or vulnerabilities
- Established and administered security related tools like an external agile pentesting provider or asset scanning provider to promote and enable self-sufficient engineering teams
- Acquired the AWS Security Specialty certification and held presentations about the exam and preparation strategies in the AWS user group Hamburg and the local Architecture Community of Practise

EXPERIENCE

DevOps Engineer - Aug 2015 - Sep 2021

immowelt Hamburg GmbH / Hamburg

- Developed and established the DevOps Mindset in an engineering team enabling them to work self-sufficient and independently
- Designed and implemented automated and environment-agnostic deployment processes to enable parallel development of multiple features using the Gitlab stack
- Worked closely with a cross functional team to revamp the property search page and its underlying components, utilizing modern technologies like AWS, React, Typescript and Java to improve user interaction and performance
- Evaluated various tools to increase the security level across the software engineering department
- Developed and established centralized Infrastructure-as-Code components to enabling the DevOps department to ensure the highly distributed cloud environments are updated and monitored

IT-Support - Feb 2014 - Jul 2015

Goodgame Studios - Altigi GmbH / Hamburg

- Provided 1st, 2nd, and 3rd level technical support in German and English for IT infrastructure, including and resolving malfunctions as well as assisting users with technical guestions
- Created technical documentation and installed, configured, and administered clients and applications
- Contributed to projects focused on Linux and live event technology
- Enabled company-wide integration of Dell KACE to simplify and accelerate deployments and updates

IT Systems Electronics Technician - Sep 2011 - Jan 2014

tectumHOME GmbH / Hamburg

- Planning and calculating smart home projects
- Installing various hardware components responsible to control the house
- Programming central controlling units from Crestron
- Creating central user interfaces
- Integrating telecommunication systems like networking devices or servers

EDUCATION

Higher Education Entrance Qualification - Apr 2014

State Trade School G18, Hamburg

Apprenticeship IT Systems Electronics Technician - Jan 2014

State Trade School G18, Hamburg

LANGUAGES

German - native

English - fluent

Spanish - basic proficiency

INTERESTS

Sport – I'm an cyclist and enjoy participating in local events or going on a Bikepacking trip

Coffee – I'm passionate about coffee and have experience demonstrating and training about different brewing techniques

Languages – I enjoy learning new languages to explore different cultures. In my spare time I am studying Spanish